quite how they got the tickets but they
did well to do so and they're here we're
waiting for a big step up in class from
Paolo Espinosa Sanchez bronze medalist
of the world championships last year
know me bat key of Italy fall in Hungary
but now representing Italy you earlier
forgot Chuck of the Ukraine no the
second of the Canadians again looking
for a slightly better performance you'll
need it if she wants to make it into the
top 12 which is where we will be at the
end of this session and now full of
beans full of life and full of words
Katie Bell of the USA watch her
preparation for every dive we have a
little chat on the chanter to herself
my leg Ogawa of japan into the last
seven now this is the order in which
they will dive five rounds of dives
remember in the women's Yulia
Martin over there's the two Chinese is
yeah bamboo
woman's 10-meter platform semi-final
they're just introducing the 18 who made
it through from an original list of 26
sadly from a British point of view no
representation Stacy Powell didn't make
it through Northey monic cladding she
was 19th last night so she missed out on
that last remaining place christian ster
of germany had a exceptional performance
last night Leon Taylor as Emma is
alongside me the 10 metre synchro silver
medalist from 2004 in Athens I think
it's safe to say Leon the standard last
night left a little bit to be desired
yeah it seemed to me that not many of
these ladies willing to make it through
to this semi-final that shown rule in
the Olympic champion only 15 years old
four years ago in Beijing tops the field
or top the field by a huge margin by the
end of the proceedings last night it's a
tough program for these young ladies
they are on again and they didn't finish
until late last night they were still
diving close to 10 p.m. obviously back
to the Olympic Village have something to
eat to rest try and turn your adrenaline
down to get some sleep and then get back
up early this morning to come in and
practice your dies from the mighty 10
metre platform their towering above all
the other diving boards this is the dive
order once again and of course the girls
do five dives each of those dives counts
and it's the total score which mean you
know you make it through you don't top
12 go through to this evening's final so
it's a lot of diving in a short space of
time
who is the fittest and who can hold it
together mentally last night
lots of faltering will we see the same
this morning I think we might see one or
two what about Monica cladding it was a
surprise to some actually she even
competed last night because she had a
quite serious injury she did what an
absolute shame money cladding finishing
19th Stacy Powell 20th so they're both
reserve one and reserve two but none of
the ladies ahead of them have been
injured in the meantime and so they're
watching on the pool side thinking what
if money cladding of course hitting a
head on the diving board in Russia only
just over a year ago and yeah
fortunately knocking as well she knocked
herself out sunk to the bottom the pool
rescued by her teammate
Robeson Baker a truly dramatic story an
inspirational story how she came back
and made the Olympic Games team at the
age of 31 her first Olympic Games such a
shame to see her not featuring today in
the semi-final alongside Stacy Powell as
well having a tough day in the diving
pool meaning reserve one and reserve -
what a shame right so just say how this
works in case you're new to diving and
haven't seen our coverage up to this
point the marks will appear on your
screen all the marks that have lines
through them will not count towards a
totally in other words the top and
bottom marks are discarded the three in
the middle will be taken as their marks
and they will be multiplied by the
degree of difficulty now in most cases
in the first round it will be 3.0 we
might go down into the twos we do go
down for the twos we only go as high in
the women's as opposed to the men's Leon
as three point three yeah let me just
explain the degree of difficulty is
assigned to each of the dives it depends
on how difficult the dive is to how high
the degree of difficulty is and in this
competition
we're see ranging from two point seven
up to a highest of three point three now
I can explain that as it goes on but
what you're looking at seven execution
judges the two highest and two lowest
marks are discounted so they have lines
through them this is so we average out
any well any amount of subjectivity to
leave three marks those are then as Bob
said total to multiply by the degree of
difficulty to give the total for that
particular tie there girls this morning
have to do five different dives in five
different directions then they have six
you know directions to choose from if
you will
forwards which is self-explanatory
backwards which is also sup it's by
inwards which is where you stand
backwards spin forwards towards the
diving board the reverse which is the
opposite which is where you stand
forwards jump away from the diving board
and spin backwards towards it and the
twist group which is where you rotate
longitudinally as well that's really
complicated and of course the sixth
group which is available on the platform
is the handstand the arm stand group and
some girls choose to do that and my co
commentator Paul baloff gets ever so
nervous when the girls or the boys do
handstands from the 10-meter platform
now they made it easy for you this
morning in as to much as the first 10
divers will all do exactly the same dive
to get a chance to compare and contrast
how good or bad or indifferent the dives
up so first 10 or opting for a 4 3 and
1/2 somersaults in the pike position as
you see on your screen 3.0 degree of
difficulty so the marks account will be
multiplied by that for all of the first
10 divers first up is Kim of the
People's Republic of Korea or she was
probably one of the surprise is making
it through just scraping in in 18th spot
that's a very steady opening dive what
you're looking for right on the end of
the diving board you notice a towel on
the end of the diving port there that's
just preference for the for the divers
it is actually a non-slip surface on the
e on the platform but some divers
preferring probably from a comfort point
of view to put a wet towel down to add
to some grip but that's a solid start
from Kim
yeah 63 is a mark you will probably see
quite a bit off because the judges tend
to go for that mid range 7 x the degree
of difficulty of use 63 there are a few
divers were waiting to up their game
considerably and here is one of them the
first of the Canadians you'll see Ross
Lee in Philly on second up of 18
remember we reduce them to 12 for the
final later today again the four three
and a half
she's had liquid off her game she
certainly was last night this young lady
wanted ones medal and he last week in
the synchronized 10 meter event with
their partners also in this contest well
it could be doing squeezing into a bike
shape a little bit more there who didn't
look very neat and tidy she's a little
bit loose as she entered the water looks
a little bit tired actually there we go
see the divers punching a hole into the
water they're spreading their hands as
they go in and sucking down all the air
with them to try and do the rip entry
which is a splash this entry not as good
as the opening dive 61.5 0 for filly on
now he comes
Maria Carillo Maria not quite completing
the dive you can see entering shorter
vertical as she hits the water I think
she needed an 11 meter platform to make
this one safely this of course only a 10
metre platform look how low she finishes
to the water the water would hit her on
a chest and then the top of her thighs
throwing up quite a lot of splash
there'll be the lowest scoring dive so
far early stages but for this young
German diver to make it through she
would need to be at the top of her game
and that's a little bit off quite a bit
off unfortunately from her point of view
so already having to play catch-up 49.5
0 with 4 and a half's and 5 sprinkled
across there and she is way off the pace
early stages now Kim Jin Ock of he was
probably good career semi-finalists in
Beijing and also the last two World
Championships oh she's emulating what
she's done in her last three big meets
and she oh one better this time it's
very good
the drivers are looking to enter the
water fantastic support from the
teammates look at the enter the water
completely vertically with no splash and
if you're doing that you're going to get
eight and upwards from the judges I
think that's the best forward three and
a half we've seen this morning from Kim
squeezing into the pipe shape heavily
taped on ankles and and calf's there
lots of these divers held together by
sticky tape and this is one of them
that's good very good
70 point five zero couple of eights and
a 7.5 to count towards the total times
three and you get the picture and you
get the calculation brittany viola it
has a big support team including her dad
it was a major league baseball legend
Frank the Americans going with a for
three and a half as indeed all the
previous four have done run over
Brittany really attacking the take off
they're cranking up the rotation which
is well exactly what you want to be
doing have a little bit of a nap there I
think it might be a bit tired from a
late finish last night
here we go squeezing into the pike shape
all looks good so far just a little bit
late from the rotation and rolls over a
touch
Stood Still get over 65 points which
will keep her in contention I'm
surprised to see her this load I'm
finished she did make one mistake though
last night to move it down the pack yeah
it was better to move up as well 60 7.50
it's a solid opening died for her that
put her in second place for the time
being now the big surprise to me last
night was this lady hello Espinoza
Sanchez bronze medalist now she never
really got going in a program perhaps
you will on this occasion yep it's still
not as good as we would expect from Paul
Espinoza multiple medallist at world
level and of course Olympic medalist
only last week in the synchronized
10-meter platform here just arching as
she goes into the water giving the
impression the dive is further over than
it actually was so over from vertical
splash comes towards us there she'll
only get sevens on that better than a
prelim but still not just good
we expect her wing for her to come to
life and show what she really is all
about because she was so impressive last
year at the world's but so far we
haven't seen anything like that kind of
form from her now the Hungarian born
Italian representing their we bat key
again same time again maybe just letting
the tide run over a vertical you can see
the sprays there from the side of the
pool it's actually like a hose pipe
spraying water just onto the surface the
reason for this is so you disturb the
surface of the water so the divers can
see exactly where they want to land so
if the water was still you could see the
bottom of the pool which is actually
five point eight meters further away so
those sprays disturbing the water so the
divers know exactly when to grab their
hands and try and enter the water she
might be a bit disturbed by that school
and actually 58.50 not quite what she
would have hoped for
remember it's five rounds and plenty of
time for reparation he only up for a
Gottschalk of Ukraine right down to dive
at number eleven we'll see exactly the
same shoes diver number six there's that
for three and a half again well that's
very tidy
she needs to squeeze into a pike shape a
little bit to get most marks from the
judges there should be no daylight in
between the thighs and the chest and as
you can see that you can almost drive a
small car through that gap it needs to
be a lot tighter but she does a very
good entry on the end of the dive there
yes yeah it's an interesting technique
normally the divers wrap around the
backs of the the calf's with the
forearms
Yuliya they're holding on with the hands
that's very difficult you need the
incredible amount of arm strength but
she gets eighths on it she does 72 puts
her in the lead a reminder to you the
judge is to not see the replays that you
see they judge it purely and what they
see in real-time so if we see anything
on the replays that they don't well
because they only get one look and we
get several making Ben feet Oh second of
the Canadians with our opening dive
there you can see the difference in the
pike shape there between Megan and luleå
squeezing in so there was no daylight in
between her body and her thighs look at
this squeezing into that tight Pike
shape completing the rotations very
comfortably just letting the dive roll
over she goes in so she won't get any
eight seven and a half's I think on this
one and I expect this lady to feature in
this evening's final ya be a big
surprise if she didn't a lot of
Canadians here to support her both at
the port and what he on TV I know in the
UK so 7.5 s gross the board times three
gives you 60 7.50 now Katie's gonna have
a chat here we go preparation as a smile
has a chat she'll count herself in and
ready to go
well it seems to work though she's got
more moves than the chess player out
there moving around quite nervous
talking to herself doing what she needs
to do but it certainly worked for
yesterday in the prelims and that's the
better start here just a little bit over
vertigo but a splash this entry
this could get some eights from the
judges and probably put a top of the
leaderboard so far in this competition
great start there from Katie Bell think
we've warmed to it certainly the crowd
have just idea synchronous before she
dives seventy-three point five zero puts
Katie Bell into the lead now my Nakagawa
of japan she had a very good freelancer
with a very small degree of difficulty
in comparison
oh now did you hear that so what
happened there she's doing the inward
and she actually smacks her feet on the
board I heard a sound now if the judges
saw that as well you'll see on the
replay here dong Oh with the toes that
isn't gonna hurt but it does why it
doesn't throw her because it dies very
good now if the judges see it they're
gonna cane her on the points so they're
gonna really penalize because of course
you're not going to hit the diving board
and because it made a loud donk sound I
think the judges will all spot that well
they should their Olympic judges let's
see well yes they do
no they do they've all spotted it that
would have got eights if it didn't so
they've decided to take off the right
amount of points all right four point
five two six point five thing is quite a
differential but obviously that's the
reason we have it even now in the middle
so we don't get too much of a wide
spread of mark so we've seen threes see
in 2.7 our upping the ante a little bit
this will be a three point one and the
first time our arm stands winning our I
can hear in the background for the crowd
yes so impressive isn't it could you
imagine just standing on the edge of a
10 metre platform anyway but let alone
doing a handstand
it seems pretty normal to me I used to
do it every day but here we go for those
of you at home look how impressive this
is and that's a beautiful dive here
that'll put her straight into the lead
she did this in the prelims yesterday
opening up on probably her best dive and
what confidence does it take to open up
your Olympic competition in a handstand
well she throws up a bit like a catapult
there and it worked very effectively
eight point five and eight Alice is
slightly higher degree of difficulty
gives her the extra marks to seventy
seven point five zero first of the two
Chinese now who you Dan sixteen years of
age I'd see this more like eight who you
Dan was a little bit off by her
standards last night and watching her in
training she doesn't seem to be as sharp
as I've seen her before
she is only 16 but she is an absolutely
phenomenal diver and that is just a
little bit off the pace he'll only get
seven and a half now from this young
lady I've seen her disappear into the
water four nines and tens on this dive
and that is back from the eight ball
right across the board seven point five
up to 8.5 we'll count to a total which
is 69 for who goes into fifth place in
round one now from Australia didn't do
the synchro ten last week as we thought
she might the second place in their
transfer here she is individual Melissa
whoo yeah very steady from Melissa woo
last night in the prelims one of the few
drivers who were diving consistently and
I'm sure she'll put in a consistent
performance here in the semi-final again
opting for the towel that's just a
comfort thing it is wet to give you a
little bit more grip or maybe not
anyway it's the divers preference needs
to be in with the color and the branding
so the towels are provided because some
divers like to use them and Melissa rue
is one and she ends up pretty good after
a first round dive yeah it goes into
joint second place seventy-three point
five zero so a nice solid opening from
the Australian four points behind the
Russian Colton over now Brittany Broman
second of the Australians 16 years of
age with her reverse two-and-a-half
somersaults with tuck slight variance
for you and only two point seven
attached to this one well what a dive I
was expecting that this is her favorite
dive she tends to open with it and it's
an impressive one so this is the reverse
this is where you stand forwards and
jump away from the diving board spinning
backwards dangerous impressive and that
is very well executed this could see
some nines and it certainly should only
16 years old and Wow she is performing
exceptionally well in her first Olympic
Games I had a very safe distance from
the board as well she's good see yes he
was not a few people getting much more
close than we would like but she has
achieved what she needed to do with that
opening dive it's very impressive 70
1.55 puts her in with the top pack in
fifth place now this I think was a
surprise this is a low tariff program
that Cristiano has but she did it to
perfection last night pretty much 2.8
inward two-and-a-half somersaults she'll
perform this in the pike position which
Leon will explain after you've seen it
yeah if you remember in the prelim this
was her weakest dive she actually laid
left herself quite a lot to do and then
you know cruise through as other girls
were faltering moving away from the
diving board missing her feet
unlike Nakagawa who tipped her toes
christine storm moving and safe for
distance away from the diving board it
is tricky to miss the diving board
because you're obviously in the pike
position which is folding at the hips
and keeping it straight through the
knees there we go so those marks are
okay but less than 60 points she'll be
off the pace yeah the degree of
difficulty reducing her options in terms
of points she can achieve and that's
gonna put her down relatively near the
bottom and panga 310 and syncro very
busy girl
she was on fire yesterday wasn't she in
the preliminaries there are teammates
cheering her on fantastic support for
all of the divers here today and look at
this Pike shape it's beautiful she seems
to have such amazing flexibility in the
hamstrings and in the lower back that
she could almost get her chin on her
ankles in the pike shape which is very
impressive it makes the rotations even
easier she could do is squeezing into a
pike shape a little bit more but I think
she's rotating that fast she was a
little bit nervous to squeeze in too
much
she starts with a good score once again
six 7.50 remember these diamonds have
had a very short recovery time they're
still competing about 12 hours ago
outstanding diver in the preliminaries
I'm gonna get by a long way Chen ruling
of China
well champion bull maybe Chen didn't
quite get to bed early enough last night
well she didn't have a choice because
she was still in here until 10:00 p.m.
that's a little bit off for this young
lady
Olympic champion at the age of 15 here
she is four years on and hasn't really
been challenged in this event since the
occasional competition that there's been
a bit more closely run but that's a
little bit off the off the mark there
for Emily and that's gonna put her while
she's not going to be top after the
first round which is unusual although we
must build a little caveat to that the
Chinese sometimes get a little bit
marked up now she has been on this
occasion 88.5 seventy-three point five
zero for the olympic gold medalists from
last time around age of 15 now 19 so
round one is completed these are the
scores remember top 12 go through bottom
six get discarded all turnover very
positive start for her Katie Bell
general in and Melissa Wu all together
so at the moment it's the competition
where to stop our Espinoza Sanchez
who'll be the last one to go through and
we would lose Rosalie and Feeny off
among others below that line of 12 26
down to 18 and then bounced 12 tonight
so just to explain the differences in
some of the dives that we're seeing so
the girls have to do five dives and five
different dives they have to cover five
different groups so basically they go in
different directions and you've seen
most of them now forwards backwards
inwards so he stands backward spin
forward to reverse which is raced and
forwards and spin backwards and also the
quest which is where you rotate them on
the longitudinal axis as well this is
the inwards coming up now for Kim inward
three and a half summer sorts with tuck
and the degree of difficulty is the
highest we have seen in the competition
so far three point to remember top
Mark's three that count we multiply by
the degree of difficulty well she does
very well very well Kim there's a little
world
lots of the ladies were a bit here and
there in the prelim that Kim made it
through squeezing in her hair it's quite
close to the diving board in fact it may
have even have touched the diving board
so that's a little bit too close for
comfort this is the dive that Monique
cladding had an accident on and you can
see how accidents can happen they just
stand back would spin forwards towards
it the judges didn't think it was too
close though they've marked her fairly
close enough for me to close seven and
six 7.20 remember the middle marks the
ones account top to bottom two discarded
the middle ones will count and the
degree of difficulty is the
multiplication that's how we arrived at
sixty seven point two zero now 14th
place after round one someone be there
for very long Rosaline filly on and a
back three-and-a-half he's a bigger dive
indeed three point three she she
struggled on that in the prelims and she
struggled a little bit again to tell for
my first dive that she looked a little
bit maybe fatigued a little bit tired
which I'm not surprised about anyway
this is a big dive she needs to squeeze
into a tuck shape a little bit more
ending up shorter vertical with their
lower back arch and throwing out quite a
bit of splash it should get over 60
points it was better than the prelims so
all it's not over for this young lady
but you can just see by her body
language there that she was finding it
tough out there today frustrating for
her just over the 61.5 she's gone down
to sixty 1.05 that was a higher degree
of difficulty on that dive as well it's
Maria Carrillo with our armed stance
which give me a chance to tell you that
she struck a head against the 10 meter
tower lost consciousness and fell into
the water just over two years ago
suffering lacerations and concussion
that kind of story to money cladding
last year she was back on the diving
board
a month later can you believe how brave
some of these divers are they come to
our arm stands a big one 23.2 i'm stand
back double somersault
one and a half twist we will see one
more
intricate than this later on yeah booze
and ours from the crowd and very very
impressive having to show a steady arm
stand balanced before to the judges
before you take off flicking off there
into the one and a half twist completing
the dive she's straight up and down on
that that'll get over 70 points seven
and a half
there we go lifting up interesting one
foot at a time
elbows have been that's incredible arm
strength here she goes look at that
overhead view any of you fancied that Oh
home mm-hmm probably not no thank you
for asking but I'll decline that offer
very kind there it is 72 from Cuyo and
she and filly or have you the battle
themselves about a second place as it
stands on to Kim Jin oke all the
People's Republic of Korea well to make
it through first semi-final and she's
getting in with three and a half
somersaults 3.2 well she's done well
there it looked like there was a
trapdoor on the end of the 10 meter
diving board just as she took off
instead of springing up through the
ankle she seems to move her hips back
and skip backwards which does mean that
she's a safe distance from the diving
board which is good but it does make the
dive more difficult to control however
Kim here does a fantastic job with a
trapdoor takeoff well done and the exits
are here here and here 60 7.20 sevens
for Kim and that puts temporarily at
least into first place ahead of the
other Kim
Brittany viola
big support team that's mum mum didn't
have a good night's sleep either
bollocks of things arm stand back double
somersault from one and a half twist
three point two you've seen this one
before you seen it executed pretty well
it's nice and the crowd as they can into
that upright position
oh it's just a little bit short of
vertical as she goes in there Britney
did all the hard work I mean imagine how
challenging it is all the blood rushes
to your head then you need to flick off
and then you hurtle towards the water
hit in the water at nearly 40 miles an
hour
and he has a lot going on 1.6 seconds it
takes to complete the dive photo just a
little short she went into the water
there the water hitting her on the chest
and the front of the legs
splash going back towards the diving
board spreading the arms they're trying
to get in without any splash a little
bit under park
yeah chick flicks for you in the diving
this morning sixty point eight zero for
Brittany that's not gonna help her cause
a great deal she's slipping down the
pecking order and third at the moment
now come on power let's see what you can
really do helmet
Espinoza Sanchez of Mexico three point
three back three and a half somersaults
classy act and she show us and underline
why that's the case
now I think you should keep quiet when
powerless driving you doing this last
night in the prelims and this young lady
is an exceptional diver but we haven't
seen it since last week in the
synchronized diving event look how high
she is she cruises this dive kick sight
but she should be out of that dive
earlier over she goes
lots of splash enough splash Wow
mini wave mini surfboards time for some
surfing she ready she has given herself
a lot to do on the basis of that dive in
there and she slipped yeah like last
night she was 18 at one point looked
like she wouldn't make it only 12 today
not that comfort blanket of those six
places today she is in the bottom place
at the moment and struggling which I
find amazing they owe me back II of
Italy back two and a half summer sorta a
two point nine degree of difficulty on
this she'll perform it in the pike
position oh that's a bat around the back
of the head there she didn't look with
back with her chin and reach back with
the arms and let me tell you when the
water hits you that hard around the back
of the head that does not tickle oh my
goodness yeah this is why divers get so
many neck injuries all she goes in
interesting Paola showing you the
backward three and a half which caused a
carries a three point three degree of
difficulty this is backward two and a
half in the pike position easier only
two point nine so it needed to be better
than that from this young Italian well I
was telling you a little kind of wobble
here with a few of the divers this
happened last night where one seems to
trigger another triggers another need to
me just to steady the ship and get back
on target and back on track maybe it's
Elia for a cop truck the person who can
do that is that in with three and a half
three point to fifth after round one
well it's pretty good straight up and
down just a little bit too much splash
but it's three point two degree of
difficulty and as long as she's steady
she's got 72 on the first round I don't
think she'll be as high as that on
second mind I'm just throwing up a
little bit too much splash but she'll
get over 60s mid sixties probably and
that will be good enough to keep her
middle of the pack which is where she
needs to be to make it through to the
top 12 going through
yeah 64 not as good as our opening dive
which is 72 that was a high degree of
difficulty this time of course and she
goes for the time being at least into
second but she won't remain there for
too long no equal ninth after round 1
still not quite in the groove three
point three back three and a half
somersaults once more in the tuck
position for Canada's Megan Ben feet OH
or she does very well she made a little
bit of a mess of this in the prelims
that made it more difficult for her to
to finish in the top of the field and
she difficut fight back and this is much
more like it squeezing into the Tuck
shaped up shape bending at the hips and
at the knees hanging on to the shins
with both hands squeezing into it almost
a little ball you can only see where
you've been on this dive so you have to
predict where to place your feet where
she does perfectly and plunk sit right
on ahead seventy five point nine good
die yeah good I put her in the lead for
the time being now the pocket rocket
from Columbus USA twenty four years old
six stone eleven dripping wet with lots
of words to add talking to
I think she's talking to herself yes now
it was the counting in the basement is
it five six seven eight sometimes one
two three verse two and a half
or she's just well there's such a tricky
dive this is the reverse two-and-a-half
she's electing to do it in the pike
position which is two point nine degree
of difficulty she did it in the Tuck
position it would be only two point
seven so you get pretty close with your
toes and she was hanging on into a pike
shape too long there you can see the
dive goes over let's check out this
overhead camera shot
oh it's enough to make you well I'm not
sure but anyway she goes over too much
splash yeah 56 points she won't be happy
with that six point five across the
board fifty six point five five and that
just knocks her down a peg or two she
was second equal to round one waiting
for something really to come to life
maybe my neck Ogawa could be that person
no Nakagawa obviously lost over
confidence and whenever bob says watch
this dive up they seem to go oh hang on
a second that's too much pressure
anyway Nakagawa hitting her feet on the
first opening dive which put him into
18th here well what a shame all the
aerial work was fantastic spinning you
know as well it's all good what an
absolute change you should just come out
now but instead she comes out a little
bit later rolls over onto her back and I
think that'll be her campaign good is
over with too poor dives just incredible
how many divers in both the
preliminaries and this are not splitting
their entries forty-eight exactly for
the Japanese and you know we may not see
her back for the final on Thursday
evening Juliet Colton over great start
well she got now
well she sneaks that in she's very very
low on the water this is a tough dive
three point three degree of difficulty
but she's a tough diver here we go
jumping up as high as you can
squeezing into that tuck shake waiting
waiting waiting and then she pops out
with just oh just about enough time to
spare and she's done very well there
because that could have been a lot you
know shorter than it was she must keep
the splash down very good indeed judges
think they're sixty nine point three
zero remember all the marks without
lines through them count towards total
multiplied by the degree of difficulty
and those people cheering in all the
time so that's why we're reminding you
soon so I feel a bit fed up with our
explanations who you Dan sixteen from
China in with three and a half
somersaults with tuck we're three point
two in degree of difficulties and ballet
dancer's posture there Wow there's not
much of who you Dan and I'm always
surprised when I see her into the water
with that much splash I wonder how she
manages that normally we used to herd
disappearing into the water here we go
all looks good so far and then just goes
loose through the body and that's where
all the splash gets thrown out the
aerial work is spot-on she comes out
there dive hiking out really class he
doesn't lock out the elbows on the
finish and therefore gets let's have a
look doesn't quite yeah it doesn't quite
lock out the elbows and think it's like
a earthquake which goes right through
the body and it's a splash that holding
the back of a head she's hurt a neck or
tell me a word or two which probably
won't be any consolation for the Chinese
as we move to the Australian Melissa
whoop here comes the three point two we
will see a three point three by the way
very soon arm stand back double
somersault one and a half twists
well just entering the water short of
vertical which means that municipal you
won't get more than 6s on that just
needed a bit more of a pop off the top
there so needed to push with their arms
a little bit stronger just to give
yourself a little bit more clearance
going in it's a very neat dive until we
get into the water and then or just you
can see the water moving back towards
the diving board
yeah still waiting for somebody to take
this competition - scruff of the neck
and nobody yet he's doing so with 64
puts it into fifth place then comes her
teammate the younger of the two
Australians but no up 16 years of age is
Brittany Groban and it's a in with three
and a half we're tuck within degree of
difficulty three point two oh yes well
she nailed her first round died 71
points on a very low degree of
difficulty 2.7 this is three point two
and that is the best we've seen of the
competition so far what a tie from this
young lady only 16 years old and acting
like she's been in the Olympic Games
before this could get high 70s I'm not
sure whether the judges will be awake
enough to go higher than that but let's
wait and see well they like it and we
like it 81.6 0 for Brittany who has to
travel what two hours backwards and
forwards in Brisbane to do her diving up
at 4:15 every voice I don't think an
early start is worrying her too much
Kristen Stewart of Germany just upping
her
ante here 3.2 now for a back two and a
half somersaults with one and a half
twists and she's currently in 15th place
so need to move up three to be back
tonight
we have very very clean entry into the
water even though we're aerial work is
not as good as some of the other divers
story quite weak in comparison with her
takeoffs which means the die finishes a
little bit lower and some of her fellow
athletes but look at that entry into the
water I get seven and a half's you get
even more if she was able to jump a
little bit higher
that's three point two would be a good
total score - it is we're seven point
five times the degree of difficulty
there we get landing in those Olympic
rings yet if they're landing in the
Olympic rings they've gone a bit too far
so a bit of a marker for you and Ella
hand of Malaysia well in the prelims
here she goes with dive number two in
the semi final back two and a half
somersaults with Mike 2.9 she nailed it
in the prelims and she's done it exactly
the same again there we are
the coach is capturing every single dive
for post diving analysis this is what
you did well this is what you could do
better next time and another beautiful
diving coming out the dive very very
early so need 2.9 to grip difficulty so
it needed to be nails I think she'll get
a bag full of nines for this and so she
should superb diving spectacular yeah
she's good she was good last night she's
good today seventy five point four zero
for Pandora and that will lift her up
the standings more people concentrating
and wondering whether they'll be back
tonight 7 World Series victories this
year for this lady general in the
Olympic and World Champion in with three
and a half summer sorts with tuck three
point two second at the moment and into
the lead she goes Wow people wandering
off shaky first round dive from the
Olympic champion will she will she come
out all guns blazing in my own umber to
the answer is yes this will go sailing
over 80 points beautiful entry into the
water look at that overhead shot very
strong safe distance from the diving
board technically nyeon perfect
great dive hard after the prelim see
anybody beating up and on the evidence
of that I've seen to be topping her in
the semis either general in eighty 3.20
last to go in round two so a lot of
cogitation and contemplation going on
between the a team divers as they try
and work out what they need to do to
qualify not a problem for Chen or indeed
for browbone at the moment down to nine
fairly secure it gets a little bit more
wobbly and a little bit more anxious
certainly for Brittany viola who's not
in there rosin in Philly on who's not in
there and look at that how that's
Espinoza Sanchez bronze medalist from
last year at the World Championships 16
after round two
on to Round three and spray could Jesse
round they were we're trying to find
their little place to have it at all
maybe a little nap listen to some music
get back in the concentration zone cos a
long time between dives for them not as
long as it was in the semis in their
fighting their prelims but in the series
they have to wait with 20 minutes we get
a chance to go again here's Kim Wong
yang are the People's Republic of Korea
this is the bigger of the arm stand back
somersaults is a triple in the Tuck
position three point three this is worth
well Kim's having the meat of her life
Wow only just getting into this
semi-final and that is three out of
three and that's the most difficult dive
here we are in the handstand the donkey
kick is it's sometimes known flaking in
generating the rotation and she sneaks
her entry and that could get 70 points
and if it does this young lady will be
well within the reach of an Olympic
final well she was 12th of the World Cup
meeting here earlier in the year how she
likes this venue likes that diving board
likes the atmosphere in this place
seventy point nine five the Kim she's
the first of the divers to go above 200
mostly in Philly on not seen the best of
her so far 14th place she currently
stands means she would not be returning
but plenty of time to make up that
margin three point two in were three and
a half
we're tuk for the Canadian oh it needed
to be better than that she's struggling
with of entries today you can see lots
of the divers in Roseland there with
huge wrist supports because of the
impact into the water and really she
needed to be cleaner in just going loose
through the body she goes in throwing up
a load of splash it will get sevens
maybe live less because of the amount of
splash and she'll still be struggling
and see yeah couldn't quite get the
hands together to punch that clean entry
into the water she knows what she did
wrong normally when she's performing
well as a big broad smile on her face
it's just a grimace
and facial expressions probably tell you
all you need to know about how this
competition is unfolding for her 64
doesn't really cut it
she needs to be looking at 70s and 6161
64 so far
Maria Carillo of Germany down to the 2.8
s now so she's not gonna make up much
ground with this and this is absolutely
perfect an inward two and a half summer
sorts with pike oh no she's way over way
over the in were two and a half in the
pike position importantly move away from
the diamond but we saw Nakagawa hit her
toes on this dive no mistakes here for
Maria moves away oh no she does she hits
the diving board but I didn't notice
that but she doesn't land flat on her
back maybe that was the reason why so
the judges are penalized because of the
entry into the water
yeah just tipping her toes slightly
they're not quite a big dunk like
Nakagawa but it was just a little scrape
big donk in terms of the score though
whew thirty three point six zero four
was count towards a total it's a meager
one and that will drop her right down
she wasn't in the top 12 anyway she's
gonna be even further adrift now Kim Jin
Ock all the People's Republic Korea 21
year old she wasn't semi-finalists in
Beijing and at the last two World
Championships oh she's emulated that and
the moment she's on course to go to the
final back three and a half summer sorts
with tuck top degree of difficulty 3.30
no she's made a little bit of an air up
it wasn't so good in training I was
watching this is always gonna be the
bogey die for her I think that's gonna
put pressure on her making it through to
the final
just waiting too long in the shape as
you can see that over vertical loads of
splash coming up well she'll get
penalized heavily from the judges and
she has some work to do on her two
remaining dives down among the very low
marks at moment 33 followed by 44 only
4.5 s on a high tariff dive but a big
dent in her hopes of coming back
now onto bristly viola missed the whole
of 2010 covering from two foot surgeries
they really are patched together and
just held together with bits a string
and bits of plaster sometimes on these
divers especially on the 10 meter board
here she is with her in with three and a
half some sorts with tuck 3.2 just
outside the qualification places in 13
oh and that might not meet well that
definitely won't move up into contention
to make this final real shame just
needed to be a little bit more confident
on the exit of the dive there the
takeoff is good she squeezes in tight
just comes out a little bit too early
and then enters the water with the
backside sticking out which is incorrect
you need to be completely vertical so
you just straighten out a little bit
more wow that's not even going to get
over 50 points I don't think super
slow-motion just showing you there that
she isn't quite completing the dive mmm
49 follows of 44 follows of 33 and at
the moment the judge is not seeing what
they want and the die was not performing
the way they want either and the big
shake-up going on in the pecking order
Espinoza Sanchez reverse three and a
half three point three with tuck
oh it's better that's she is the only
diver doing this dive in the competition
they reverse three and a half we used to
be three point four degree of difficulty
now it's only three point three and I
disagree with that downgrading I think
FINA have got it completely wrong there
this is super tricky you only ever see
the men perform this dive Espinoza
showing her class here but not nailing
it
Wow will we see a shock are we seeing a
shock is she gonna make it through no
fifty six point one zero doesn't
indicate she will and she's got two more
rounds to get this right and to turn it
around and she's giving herself an awful
lot to do there meat bat keep of Italy
back two and a half of somersaults one
and a half twists currently in 17th
place so needs to step it up now yeah
it's one of her better dives 3.2 yep the
back two and a half somersaults with one
and a half twist you've seen lots and
lots of girls using this this morning
here we go generating the rotations
swinging the arms wrapping into the
twist this is a twist group of dive here
most of the girls will use this dive
this morning they just choose to use it
at different times you can place your
dives in any order you choose to so it's
often a game of tactics when do you use
your best dive when do you use your
weakest dive so bhakti was still some
work to do after a poor second round
dive
whoopee we're into the seventies at last
we've waited a while for that 72 for
back heat and with everybody else
faltering it does move her up a few
spots getting closer to qualification
now yulia Ragab chuck of ukraine back
two and a half only 2.9 on this oh it's
pretty good a little bit too much splash
being thrown up but it's very neat and
tidy 2.9 degree of difficulty lower than
what we've been seeing so it needed to
be good this young lady's going very
well this morning one of the few
actually beautiful Pike shape great toe
point just tipping over there as she
went into the water so probably maybe a
couple of sevens
see how mean the judges are but she does
go over
I'm not sure I think a judge you get a
bit fed up with this you know 6.5 rather
than sevens just waiting for somebody to
set like to this competition and really
make us in theater seen some good time
here caused by the Chinese but outside
that open from Australian TV know it's
very good to be fair that's right we've
had to but the majority of divers are
funny really hard this morning to get
going now Megan Ben feet oh now is your
time fourth in Shanghai world champs
fourth in Rome in with three-and-a-half
somersaults were tuck three point two
for the Canadian currently in fourth
place
yep she sneaks it in there's a coach
Archer Miranda showing his appreciation
because it's all about being consistent
in this young lady that's three out of
three for her it's a little low on the
water but she still gets in seven and a
half so I think coming her way just
showing the ankle snap there on the
take-off in order to generate the
rotation that's a lot of dive to fit in
it's three point two another day seventy
point four zero wouldn't be that special
but today it pretty much is because
nobody's getting into that kind of a
Charlotte at the moment now welcome to
the Katie Bell chat show little chats
with self their chance it to herself the
reposition of the feet about ten times
now the inward three-and-a-half to
follow we tuck 3.2 over 24 year old
American oh wow
so first two were good and the third one
which she actually did a great job in
the prelim she's made a mistake oh she's
near the diving board and then maybe she
knows she is so she hangs on way too
long look at that huge wave back towards
the diving board they're showing that
she's over rotated that's gonna be super
low 30s yeah I think we were a little
sport with the men's three meter the
other night I think we expected the
level to continue and it just has it
with the women so far maybe the final is
where things will really take off no
these divers are taking off the way they
want thirty five point two zero and she
may not be returning tonight
it's a battle of those who who don't
want to make it rather than those who do
my Nakagawa up to the top of her range
three point three back three and a half
summer sorts for the Japanese oh my is
having a very very tough day out there
how frustrating she is a very good
divers he's a super been terrific dies
from her in the polymer he's one of the
few who were shining hitting her feet on
the first dive and that is completely
thrown her for for three and a half last
round was mediocre and this one as well
her most difficult dive be back with
three and a half in the top position
very poor indeed what a shame for
Nakagawa she's a great diver and she
will definitely not be going through to
the final
that's three poor dives oh my oh my
42.9 zero for Nakagawa yeah she's not
giving herself really much of a chance
of making it through other people
faltering but she's fortunately more
than most yulia colton over russia for
three and a half he get to get on with
it
no yet and you can see why she wants to
get her dives done that's three out of
three for the twenty three-year-old from
russia some good diving last night
finishing in the business end of the
field and i'm pretty sure with another
two
dives have this standard she will
continue to move up the pack Olympic
medal all the way back in Athens very
very young then with her partner in the
synchronized ten meter and here she is
her third Olympic Games yeah six 7.50
that's by the standard this morning
pretty decent and that will put her for
the time being at least at the top of
the pile second in Shanghai winner in
Sheffield you may have seen her last
year in the grand prix event up there 16
year old who you Dan and it's armstand
time everybody hold your breath double
somersault one and a half twists free
position
well that's more like it from who you
Dan still throwing up a little bit too
much splash for my liking but the entry
into the water was vertical and just
used to see in this young lady or young
16 year old dive so much better than
this it'll get eights
but I've seen a score nines and upwards
on this and Wally's missing on that it's
a splash the century and I'm surprised I
haven't seen her go into the water
completely clean as yet in this
competition or in the preliminaries
that means two medals are up for grabs
if who doesn't up her game to what she
can do generally and at the end looks
pretty untouchable though at the moment
here doesn't you just 8.04 who you Dan
seventy six point eight zero ko she sent
me a chat going over the dive and the
pupil is taking it all on board
Melissa woo sixth in Beijing at the
World Championships in Rome in 2009 back
three and a half somersaults three point
three in the comfort zone at the moment
in position eight but we've seen what
can happen to the others well done
Melissa there's Matthew Mitchum an
Olympic champion from Beijing in the
platform event cheering on whistling
away and Melissa and she's done very
well there the take-off is weak so she
has to wait and wait and wait and then
she pops out at the right time very neat
little bit short of vertical she'll
probably sneak sevens from the judges
and that's a good effort especially when
those around are losing their heads and
faltering like a house of cards out
there again like the prelims yeah solid
sixty nine point three exactly of the
prelims it's with obviously fewer
competitors this time but they're just
following on where they left off last
night now the very impressive today
sixteen year old Brittany Brogan and
she's gonna go for the arm stand as well
falling off the back Australian
colleague seen this a few times already
three point two degree of difficulty on
the arm stand back double somersaults
with one on half twists
oh great technique very very strong on
the takeoff and she packs it right up
with another nailed entry we're looking
for splash the sentries and the judges
are gonna award that very highly indeed
Wow what an impressive performance if
this young lady continues to dive like
this and she can replicate this in the
final well I'm going to put my money on
her for a medal how about that
you're going to go out on a limb I'm
with you gets a good odds for us we're
although we're not allowed to back to
work for the BBC but your army seventy
six point eight zero and can have a
sportsman's bet if you like I go back to
school in there well you actually old
enough to bet okay seventy six point
eight four broman takes her twelve
points clear now Kristin steer is gonna
go for the same thing can she get
anywhere near the 76s tent at the moment
so coming back tonight for the Sammy's
again yeah going from strength to
strength as she did in the preliminaries
that week first round dive but this
against row a little bit you know she
struggles on the takeoffs and this one
is well it's actually okay but you can
see if finishing quite low to the water
and she somehow manages to sneak a rip
entry and that could get a seven and a
half which because of the degree of
difficulty three point two should go
over seventy points and that's a good
score anything over seventy this morning
is very impressive because it's been a
rarity and seventy-two it is now and a
pang you come all the armed stand in a
rush exactly the same one say we do go
up to three point three on some of the
arm stands but and not trying to cram it
all in slightly easier that's all
relative of course back double
somersault with one and a half twists
currently in fifth place
now you're getting to see like for like
here so the previous you know three
divers now including pendolino have
performed this and Schembri limb will
perform it after as well so it's really
nice to see there's slightly different
elevations that the girls are getting
from their you know take offs handle
eller they're just cranking the dive a
little bit too much a little bit too
much rotation here which means that she
rolls over a vertical which is a shame
because if she'd have just popped it up
a little bit higher then she'd have had
more control on the entry but still very
consistent today 70 points a dive mmm
that's what the coach is instructing her
obviously too late for this round but
that's what she needs to do tonight when
surely she will return she's currently
in fifth place but they class act she
was so far ahead of the field last night
it was untrue like she was in a
completely different competition the
olympic and world champion chain rule in
1920 later this year arm stand back
double again oh yeah yes well almost
completely ripped entry just throwing up
a little bit too much splash great
takeoff very well super control one and
a half twist double somersault in she
goes extending a lead with that one I'm
sure she'll get close to 80 points
fantastic third round dive from Chen
well I'm tempted to say put the gold
medal around her neck now but until you
have a final to come yet the five more
dives this evening and things can go
wrong as we have seen this morning but
she's been on top of her game when
others have been faltering and she has a
lead of nine points over the rest of the
field so after round three two more to
come five rounds in women's six rounds
in men's we are looking for the top 12
to progress to the final tonight and all
nine of them are there so far see those
who are scrapping for the minor places
Rosalie and Finney on in eleventh so we
lose back key viola we are going to lose
Paolo Espinosa Sanchez that's a huge
surprise really is
she's made KC bail as well who really
good sequence of dives last night so a
couple of big casualties on the way and
that I was locked into their music
knocked into perhaps their emails and
their Twitter accounts trying to take
themselves awake now on to round four of
the women's 10-meter platform a semi
final top 12 to progress yang is doing
just that she's ninth place going into a
pan ultimate dive which is the back
three and a half somersaults with tuck
three point three is the degree of
difficulty on the opening dive of round
four or you could prove to be critical
Kim of course nailing three out of three
wow that's a biggest degree of
difficulty and she hasn't completed the
dive and shorter vertical and that could
see her missing out on a place in the
final that's a real shame you know
thirty sixty three 67 and 70 and she's
gonna be nowhere near that with the
marks on this one what the judges say
forty one point two five how to undo a
great sequence of dives in one fail
swoop spin the leaf of time being but
she's not gonna stay there for very long
I'll go hurtling down the standings
there's no margin for error for Rosaline
filly on either of Canada and this is
the slightly more detailed if you like
I'm stand 33.3 just trying to get
together there's a triple somersault on
the back of this
oh she's waited until now to stake her
claim she was in 11th after the third
round so this needed to be good this is
a highest degree of difficulty equal
highest three point three so armstand
flicking there we are strong flick
intercept just holding on to the top of
her kneecaps there well that's the first
entry that she's almost got on this one
that's going to get sevens and 7.5 s
which means with the degree of
difficulty of three point three she'll
be over 70 points and has bobbers
mentioned anything over 70 points will
put you well in contention for making a
spot in the final yeah so providing
nothing goes terribly wrong in the last
round she should be there seventy four
point two five for Rosaline a 25
year-old from Canada not being maria
Kayo's de from berlin twenty
two-year-old in the back two and a half
somersaults like two and a half some
ourselves one and a half twist lots of
the the girls will be finishing on this
dive you'll see this dive from a lot of
the competitors in the last round here
maria Epting to use this one as their
fourth round dive and unfortunate for
her not working very well today entering
the water short there you can see the
splash being thrown back towards the
diving board have a look at the strain
on the face of the divers is they're
battling against gravity and different
forces trying to pull them in different
directions
all in fractions of seconds incredible
kind of mark fifty two point eight zero
and I'm afraid her chances of coming
back tonight look very remote at this
stage Kim Jin okay time to do the arm
stand slightly different one this to
remember this one yesterday Bob this is
one where she placed her nose on the end
of the platform or diff she's going to
do the same again three point one
forward double somersault one twist see
how close she gets today yeah right on
it again yes she just well the
interesting techniques you're most
places heard knows what she does place
her nose on the towel on the end of the
platform
and then flicks forward with the with
the legs in order to generate the
forward rotation in order to then come
out of the Ford rotation into the twist
and then into the Pike shape such a
challenging guide and an interesting
here we go
Oh forehead on the board like a head
spring in gymnastics no wonder she has a
towel there that can't be very pleasant
at all we are seeing some different
techniques aren't we some very
individual interpretations of some of
these dives and in her case it produces
a sixty five point one zero seven across
the board multiplied by the degree of
difficulty as I arrive with the marked
remember those marks with lines through
do not count are the ones that don't
have lines through do now Brittany viola
your chance to step up here and it's not
a dive that's gonna help you do it
greatly two point nine lower tariffs
back two and a half or yeah you see a
lot of squash being thrown up and spot
mentioned two point nine puts the
pressure on the diver to really execute
the die superb Lee well in Brittany well
she does a good job here all looks good
so far all she needed was to disappear
and instead she just tips a little bit
over throwing up quite a bit of splash I
don't think we're gonna see viola
progressing unless of course she can do
an eye on perfect last round i but
anyway anything can happen in this
competition already so let me get ahead
of myself in fact i'm gonna take back my
last statement and let's wait and see
fifty two point two zero i'm really not
what sure quite what to say about the
next competitor kids whatever i say has
an adverse effect on her performance so
all I would say is here's our Espinoza
Sanchez in with three and a half
well I think she dives so much better
when you just keep quiet Bob so I'm not
sure what to make of that
but Paulo is in 15th laughter the third
round this is much more like it this is
how we're used to seeing your dive and
this still could be better but I'm just
gonna let that go and say that's great
it'll get seven and a half and normally
more custom ter eight and eight point
five s and upwards but a little bit over
four for that so here we are 7.5 s as
predicted 72 needs to be better to make
that comeback though she does do it best
when I say nothing at all mg no e bat
key or Italy formally are hungrier so
she was born in Budapest and she will go
with an inward three and a half
somersaults we're tuck three point two
hurry in 13th place so looking out for
yourself get this right she could leap a
place or two and be back for the final
oh yeah that's certainly going to help
her campaign just on the cusp 13 and 3.2
big degree of difficulty and she's got a
low degree of difficulty to finish on so
she knows that pressure was on this dive
her fourth of iron dive you've seen this
a few times before this is the inward
three and a half and that's gonna get
mid-70s and if it does really strong
charts provided she nails a last dive of
going through which would be a superb
achievement for Naomi there are a lot of
provisos today as you noted a lot of
caveats from our seventy six point eight
zero eight across the board seventy six
point eight zero that's very nice work
by Naomi up into second he only ate for
a Gottschalk of Ukraine we'll see you
love the fourth round dives being armed
stance here comes another and it is the
very highest tariff 3.32 problems with
this last night
I'm stand back triple
well it's such a shame really because
the take-off was superb the rotation was
fast enough and then maybe she just fell
asleep halfway through because she
wasn't ready to come out of the dive and
then comes out way too late over she
goes that's gonna get five and a half
six sixes I think she's got enough of a
buffer to keep herself in contention to
qualify as you have to do some work on
that this afternoon before the final but
this young lady's done very well this
morning some of them haven't that julia
has strong starts just a knee off over
here 56 followed by fifty four point
four five four Prague up shook but she's
up into fourth place for the time being
and that should at the moment be good
enough to see her through this one more
round still to go stand I'm and again a
three point three exactly the same arm
stand back triple somersault for Megan
Ben Peter having a much better semi file
than the preliminary and fourth in
Shanghai fourth in Rome how much was she
like to go one better in London yep well
I'm sure well the thing is people need
to to make their way through safely to
the final then you can start to turn it
on Megan it's being consistent and
that's all she needs to do for the top
of the field so far still some divers
still to come this is it three point
three she gets into a really good tuck
shape just a little bit over as she goes
into the water so the judges will give
her seven yeah seven is gross aboard
sixty 9.30 for the marks account
I'm gonna miss Katie Belanger to make
the final and looks like she's not going
to the way things are saying but she has
two more rounds she can as Leon often
says land on her head which is a good
ceremony a good expression and she could
be back but she's got some ground to
make up
smile seems have disappeared to
concentration still there though back
three and a half somersault with a
counting on a three point three I think
it might be all over for Katie Bell what
a shame because yeah it's poor first two
dies in the preliminaries and then three
blistering dies to finish earn to this
spot comfortably and now this is her
biggest I've three point three just
turning into banana woman as she goes in
their lower back arch look at the strain
through all the body in order to
generate the rotation it even looks very
quick in slow-motion you really know how
quickly these divers are moving loose as
she goes into the water the impression
of a banana and oh the judges world
mixed bag five and a half to six and a
half so she's actually got away with
that I think subconsciously you're
putting forward some pilot ideas to TV
producers here banana man would he would
he win by the skin of his teeth his
Nakagawa reverse two and a half Wow
Nakagawa is just gone unfortunately from
bad to worse for her you know an
unsteady start hitting her feet on the
platform and then since then it's just
been a shambles for it hasn't so we've
seen it in a couple of a couple of times
where divers lose the plot and we're
seeing here with mid nakagawa just can't
find to her flow at all today it's one
more dive to go such a shame I expected
this young lady my to be in the final
but no final four Nakagawa today doesn't
know like it does a 18 place and tailed
off at the back of the field
so it's the best that she will be able
to achieve in London not the same for
yulia colton over fourth place they come
to a three point two degree of
difficulty dive tuck position for the
end with three and a half
well this is the one that she bolted on
in the preliminaries yesterday evening
and it's much better job this morning in
the semifinals it's still not where it
needs to be she's a little bit low on
the water and then she kind of does a
double come out so she comes out from
the hips and then straightens her knees
it should all happen simultaneously so
the judges really penalized her in the
prelims for it but it was more apparent
than this one is actually okay so she
might get six and a half seven as if she
snaps out straightening through the
knees and the hips at the same time it
looks a lot neater and she'd probably
get AIDS but heard sevens today I
predict a look back at the scoreboard
tells her the 60 7.20 is her mark
sevens will count and yeah she's in the
comfort zone in second place we're still
a few to go who you dan and her back
three laughs somersaults 3.3 with tuck
wow what are we watching here now who
done certainly hasn't found her rhythm
or certainly hasn't found her terrific
diving that we're used to seeing I'm not
sure whether she's injured she know no
one's made any statements but she is
diving under par she was definitely
gonna make it through to the final no
doubt about that but those other medals
are wide opening if Paul Espinoza goes
out as well then we could be entering
the interesting top three yeah five
point five that's a rarity for Chinese
divers at any competition and she just
hasn't really got together 76 in the
previous dive was okay at 54 it's not
now melissa whoop of australia seventh
place with two more dives to come in
with three and a half we tuck
very good
very steady this morning formulas up in
with three and a half such good shape
sneezes together toes are pointed
bending at the hips and at the knees
little short she went in that'll go
seven and a half not quite upright
enough for an eight
look at that perfect shape in the air a
little bit sure does she went in but
very steady from whoop she'll be one of
our finalists looks very much like we
will have two Australians through to the
top twelve Lister we without 72 is
pretty much guaranteed her place she's
not been anywhere near as impressive
this young lady 16 years of age Brittany
bromans second place at the moment
here's her back three and a half well
that's where weakest I've so far but
she's a real class act this young lady I
am super impressed yep she knows she's
let the dive over rotate there but Wow
look at this jump double almost by board
level she's just out a little bit late
there if she was out earlier she would
have given herself chance just to bury
that entry it'll only get I don't know
five and a half maybe on that because
she is quite a way over vertical and
does go loose as she goes in however
three exceptional dives and one dive to
improve on she she's a medal in the
final I'm gonna go out on it to
definitely five point five and five
towards that total of fifty two point
eight zero just inched to make sure that
she's shaken a notch dirt here back two
and a half somersaults with Mike two
point nine degree of difficulty I was
about to come out with my
double-oh-seven gags but I think she's
gonna get even more than sevens on that
again opting for the slightly easier
dive so two point nine degree of
difficulty so it needed to be good it
was good in the prelims and I think
that's going to get a bag full of eight
for that effort so no double o7s for
Stewart coming out very early pulling
the dive Ryan she knows exactly where
she is very experienced being here in
many times his real last Olympic Games
at the age of twenty nine and she's
securing her berth in the final
dive after dive while she goes
contemplating another five dives in the
final later today sixty nine point six
zero four on to and pang the penultimate
diver in round four already sixth
turning 13 achieved so far just gonna
have to hurt Ali with this inward
three-and-a-half sever sorts
we're tuck a little bit weaker for Penn
develop just I think and lacking a
little bit of confidence on that she's
been attacking her dives and maybe
losing control of some of them so this
one she tried to play safe so all looks
okay so far and then she comes out to
get all oh I've got less time than I
fought just enters the water to a touch
short of vertical it won't affect her
getting through to the final lower
standard than she would have hoped maybe
she can step up a gear for the final
yeah not quite confirm yet cuz we have
one more round to go and anything it
happens we saw in the men's three meter
the other day but within sight within
touching distance of a place in the
final say class that's not quite sure
which other way to describe Chen Ruolin
but she is in a different league when
she's diving like she has been the last
two days back three and a half last dive
around there before yep she certainly is
a cut above know when challenging Chen
yesterday or today she's having it all
of own way but it doesn't really matter
this is an exceptional dive it'll go way
over 80 points is three point three
super but of course the semi-final
scores do not carry through to the final
so Chinese actually just doing a diving
display here and everyone starts at zero
at 7:00 p.m. tonight when am I tell you
she has a gap of 39 points over the rest
kinda shows you she is a different
competition altogether it's her against
the rest really and the rest of not
making any inroads on her ways of
preparing for round five
here is the standings at the end of
Round four China Canada Australia in
Ruolin been Fito and rohban and down to
nine filly on should be okay let's see
the margin between ninth and twelfth 260
plays 247 so should be enough margin for
error built in but we are going to lose
kim sanchez bowler bell hooyo and
Nakagawa well let's wait and see if
Paolo Espinosa comes out with a superb
last hour she is in within striking
distance of scraping through or to play
four on those minor places attention the
word that's often used may be overused
in sport a lot of pressure
certainly on those around the 13 14 15
mark to up their game including the
opening diver in round five 13th place
at the moment for kim eunhaeng
know cuz she finished with a flourish
back two and a half somersaults one half
twist three point to get this right and
she might be in contention for a return
in the final well get used to this dive
you're going to be seeing a lot of the
ladies using this as their final dive
the reason being is three point two
degree of difficulty and it's actually
quite easy for a three point two so even
though the degree of difficulty is the
same as some of the times we've seen
before because of this particular
technique of dive or this style of dive
one and a half twist into the Pike shape
and you can actually see where you're
going and you're in a pike position so
you look over the end of your toes and
line up into the water
seven seven point five yep seven point
five s mainly all seven point five Tsar
the ones that count anyway
72 is her final mark now she just have
to sit and wait
I see where that will be good enough
Roslyn Feeny on our Canada in Montreal
the world champ ship sin mm of 5/4 in
Rome 7th in Shanghai very consistent
performer and here it comes again back
to a half somersaults one the half
twists
yep consistency is key and certainly is
the case for Rosaline a little bit off
her game last night and again this
morning if I'm honest but still coming
through in the end
moved herself up to ninth after four
rounds and I think she'll finish the
round about that spot here in the
semi-finals securing her berth in the
final good final dive easy to compare
like-for-like with Kim just before her
probably marginally better yeah
sixty-eight point eight zero it's all
down to the judges interpretation and
where some 7.5 s on there but they just
didn't count towards total and yeah
she's fine
coach happy she'll be row to be happy
baseball in his hand yes to calm his
nerves nervous for the coaches as well
so he does start with the with the
baseball just stopped himself going a
bit stir-crazy Maria Carey oh that's too
much to do surely now yep too much to do
low degree of difficulty to finish at
first Olympic Games as she made it
through to the semifinals when lots of
the big names were faltering she managed
to stay steady enough last night to make
it through just entering the water short
here and it's the sevens across the
board finish you see the judges they're
studying the divers she accelerates by
drop-down cameras preys on the water
there to disturb the surface so the
divers can see exactly where the surface
of the water is it's a lot to think
about yeah as she walks away and there's
what you might do with the rest of today
and indeed tomorrow it's not gonna be on
the diving board for her
Kim Jin Mok in 11th place
coach watches on my name she makes a
reasonable attempt at this she won't be
back tonight back two and a half
somersaults one and a half twists in the
pike position whoa
now she was hit 11th after the fourth
round splitting the dive go over as she
went in again you'll see a lot of the
girls finishing on this dive it's three
point two so when it's like four like
it's a battle of the execution and that
is just slightly off you can see the
diver over rotating net six-and-a-half
sevens probably did she have enough of a
buffer to secure her spot in the final
she'll have an agonizing wait yeah I'm
not sure that's gonna be quite good
enough it's gonna be right on the
margins sixty five point six zero and we
have a computer screen alongside us it
shows the qualifiers nobody yet has
qualified we don't have the big keel on
our scoreboard as they come in we will
give them to you
fifteenth place now could she finish
with her best dive what she's going to
need to do now any chance of making the
top 12 15th at the moment for brittany
viola hasn't replicated what she did in
the prelims so far back two and a half
somersaults 1r twists
well she's giving it a good go that's
what's probably her best dive today mum
and dad supporting it as always I'm sure
many people behind her here made the
trip to London anyway trying to finish
with the flourish here I don't think
that's going to be good enough it's only
going to get 7 to 7 point 5 s but she
would have really needed nines to to get
a total worthy enough in this field to
get into the final such a shame expected
to see viola go through this morning
goes to show what can happen it looks
like both Americans are going to go out
here which is a bit of a surprise 70
point 4 0
and her race I'm afraid looks to be run
now hmm okay you keep quiet Bob RT this
one up this is Paola Espinosa finishing
her final dive in 14th World
Championship
Wow has she done enough when it counts I
think she has yeah
relief from the coaches she has had a
tough day out there today hasn't nailed
any of her dives her fourth line dive
was our best one and this one is of
equal standard that should get 8 little
bit over as she went in 3.2 75 points or
there abouts it's no guarantee but I
think she might just scrape in grabbing
the hands to punch a hole in the water
look at that super slow-motion if she
goes in you can see there the feet just
tipping over a vertical there yeah I
didn't want to be powerless sword of
Damocles today I'm quite glad I didn't
say anything before that dive because
she's performed her best of the day I
know what to do tonight now don't I
seventy six point eight zero and she is
up into third place Naomi backe has very
little room for error here this needs to
be spot on reverse two and a half oh and
it is two spot on right on the money two
point seven degree of difficulty point
five lower than Espinosa and Faiola and
Kim so it needed to be bang on the money
it's difficult to get higher than 65
points or less of course you nail it
like nobody's done there she could
probably get eighth in the house for
that well she certainly deserves eight
in a house let's see what the judges
think there we are look at those wrist
supports that hands grab together
entering the water sixty eight point
eight five for backe and that has put
her in a really good place in terms of
progression first of the qualifying two
is Rosalie and phillium she cannot be
overtaken by 12 other divers so she's
made it through nobody else as yet
earlier Ragab Chuck oh it needed to be
good from you Leah started off very well
and then had a little bit of a wobble
and then she's come back with a strong
finishing 12th after the first four
rounds again saving this one until last
you've seen it before it's 3.2 it's the
twisty whirly whirly one and it works
for it that's going to get well over 65
points quite as good as Paul Espinoza
she gets around the 310 mark maybe yeah
then I think that'll be good enough for
the final toffee covered in chocolate
where they just II really really hmm
sixty-eight point eight zero for pro got
Chuck and she might be back Chuck later
on today on - Megan Ben Fito of Canada
back two and a half somersaults one and
a half twists she has moved up the
rankings and there's second place it's
been a good progression by Megan and
there is that much favored last round
over the back two and a half of one half
twists our finishes off in style that's
two Canadians through to this woman's 10
metre platform final later on today 7:00
p.m. local time already Olympic bronze
medalist last week with her partner
Rosalynn fee on both Rosaleen and Megan
through to the final superb last dive
and probably good enough to earn her
second behind Chen when Fito through
finis on through that key through all
with queues beside their names they can
join the queue and the net mind on this
occasion Katie Bell may I see her bang
out of the competition as she were never
to be will do now back to an hour
somersaults one and a half twists one
more time for old times sake the
counting
oh it's a good time to finish on just
arching through her back if she goes
into the water going over in over as she
enters here we go wrapping the arms into
the one and a half twist folding into
the pike shape squeezing in just arching
through a lo about there giving the
impression that divert is a little bit
more untidy it's a good time to finish
but that will not be good enough to
break 300 and certainly not good enough
to go through to the final that's it for
her no more which gives her a hug
consoling Pat I'm not sure his name is
Pat Burton Anton Nakagawa of Japan back
two and a half somersaults one and a
half twist three point two great 18th is
unlikely to be where she fishes up or
she's finished with a good one I'm so
pleased for Nakagawa this young lady is
a fantastic diver showing what she can
do in the prelims but unfortunately an
unsteady start to her semi-final meant
that the wheels came off and they
tumbled down the road but she's managed
to put them back on the vehicle now
nails her last dive but way too much to
do and that's a shame for my she'll be
back 25 years old will she stay on till
Rio
how does she finish seventy five point
two zero she'll be thinking honey I
could have done that more consistently
then I will be thinking about a top 12
place as it is 18th is where she will
finish Julia Colt Innova has to be a
medal contender if she continues with
this good consistent form she's shown
over the first two competitions it comes
to back two and a half
yet very consistent from Yuliya that
she's up to gain from the semies and I
think she'll be a top-five finish which
is very impressive from this young lady
one and a half twist you know this into
the pike shape beautiful toe point
little short she went in there just
stopping the dive a little bit early she
just needed to let it come round a
little bit more some improvements can be
made in between now and tonight maybe
she's saving the best to later inspired
by Ilya Zakharov standing at the top of
the podium Oney well how long ago was
that now not yesterday the day before
17.4 zero for Carlton over because I've
been feeling rather responsible for this
I'm so delighted to the Espinoza Sanchez
has made the final overslept tonight if
she hadn't on to who you'd am 16 year
old Chinese to finish off her program
oh she is all over the shop Wow Benny
was shambo's from heat and right from
the word go I'm not I'm perplexed as to
why this is actually happening this
young lady's on the Chinese team and
she's on the team for a reason and that
he's very under par one and a half twist
two and a half somersaults shorter she
goes in and very low score from who you
done she follows a 54 with a 56 she will
make the final than not very impressive
from who you Dan today now on - Melissa
Wu of Australia six place so provide
nothing goes terribly wrong on this
which we wouldn't wish on her of course
a back two and a half again with Mike
you've got used to this type right now
as she used to it can she finish with a
decent mark oh yes she can the best till
last but Melissa whoo he's been diving
steady in Matthew Mitchum there
whistling and cheering and cheering and
so he should be that's a fantastic dive
there we go lots of the girls finishing
on this one and Melissa whoo
showing her class securing her spot in
the ceilings final with eights I would
imagine
across the board well the marcsa got
gradually higher 64 69 72 and she rounds
off her bring out with a 70 6.80 lives
her up to second at the time being mind
bent feet oh and above colton over if
she's been impressive what do we say
about this young lady 16 years of age
Brittany Robin can opting to go for the
same dive the majority of divers have
gone for in the last round third and she
underlined her third place after this
well I picked you can easily expanding
diving from this young lady today the
support and this crowd very appreciative
of all the divers especially the ones
that are nailing their dives you become
an expert as the competition goes on
you're looking for the splash less entry
completely vertical and that's exactly
what this young lady delivers beautiful
diving and she is my tip for a medal
well see what the bookies say everywhere
slide from dive number four you know
it's been exemplary 71 81 76 and 76
again from Brittany bromanor she can get
round for assorted she is definitely in
with a great chance tonight an
Australian medal and they've been few
and far between us Olympics heavenly
Christian stir of Jeremy snipe variants
for us the dive that most people started
with in the first round forward three
and a half summer sorts with pike for
her to finish yeah not the best effort
for Kristine running out of room a
little bit and the takeoff do let it
down a little bit the entry into the
water is always very solid for her this
time however just a little bit loose as
she goes in not quite straightening out
completely throwing up a little bit of
splash it will still get seven and a
half's opting to use the towel it's just
a comfort thing the sprays on the water
showing he dives exactly where it is and
Strayer through to her Olympic final
yeah she's made it through and the
queues aside European out so the name
still waiting see if pre-op chip has
made it she hasn't yet got that Cuba
side here named but and a pang has done
all the good work early on so she
doesn't have a nervous last dive the
back two and a half somersaults one half
twists 3.2 yep it's tidy it's clean into
the water a little bit Rowley so she
doesn't quite straight now completely as
she enters the water so my opinion she's
giving it too much beans on the start
there cranks up the dive
and just doesn't quite control it
properly it'll get 7.5 s and she's
definitely in the final an interesting
enough trend reel in up next doesn't
even need to do a last dive
she's already qualified it's impressive
isn't it it is impressive and just shows
how far ahead of everybody else she is
7.5 in Pandora and that will mean that
she is fourth ranked to the final and
very happy to be there but nobody can
hold a candle to chain rule in she has
been absolutely mustard today back to
1/2 along with pretty much all the other
competitors in the last round to finish
well now you see me now you don't
generally disappearing into the water
and just outclassing this field quickly
bro bird looking on they're looking at
the scoreboard Jeremy Lin way over 400
points she'll probably be maybe even 50
points ahead of the rest of the field
and she is a class act what a set of
dives we've been treated to and it's her
gold this evening to throw away if she
chooses to do so and I don't think she
will
now what is the gap between her and the
rest we'll see in a moment eighty four
point eight zero nine 98.5 and that is a
tremendous way to finish she's never
been below 73 and in four rounds up
above 80 and though he's got even close
to that
no reexpress job done I'll see the gold
is not yet won but it would be a big
surprise if she doesn't come back and do
just that this evening so after the
final round round five all the women's
timmy to platform general in all are 48
marks ahead of Megan Ben Peter then the
impressive Australians today they're be
battling up maps for the bronze later
because the other Chinese who you Dan
down in ninth place and
on the other three to make it through
that key Espinoza Sanchez just did it
and for a gotcha - and Missy up by one
point four points in the end Kim on Yang
and no place for the two Americans
Brittany viola and Katie Bell both gone
not to return
so that's the semi-final of the woman's
10 metre platform done chin rule in the
outstanding competitor in it 12 will
return for the final seven o'clock
British summer time
yeah the Aquatic Centre in London's
Olympic Park hope you both join us for
that and see who's gonna pick up the
minor medals so I think at this stage we
know where the gold is going to go from
Leon Taylor and myself Bob Ballard thank
you for joining us and we'll talk to you
and see you soon
[Music]
you